A Guide to the Norfolk (Va.) Dept. of Public Works, Architectural Drawings and Plans, 1899-1934
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Norfolk (Va.) Dept. of Public Works, Architectural Drawings and Plans, 1899-1934
Library of Virginia
35996
250 sheets of mostly blueprints, some India ink on linen, Diazoprint, and Sepia prints (61 x 91 cm. or smaller)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to architectural and engineering plans and drawings of current governmental buildings requires a written request from the prospective user and written authorization from the appropriate authority within the agency occupying the facility. See Archives staff for further information.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from City of Norfolk, Department of Public Works, Norfolk, Va., n.d.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Department of Public Works was created when Norfolk adopted the a City Manager-style system of government in 1917. Section 52 of the city charter sets forth the administrative departments of government- Law, Public Works, Public Welfare, Public Safety, and Finance- under the City Manager. The Director of the Public Works Department was required to be an engineer by profession with experience in municipal engineering. The department would oversee the construction, improvement, repair, maintenance, and use of all public streets, sewers, culverts, canals, viaducts, public highways, sidewalks, drains, ditches, pumping stations, dams, wharves, landings, docks, parks, playgrounds, cemeteries, etc.
Within the Department of Public Works were the City Planning Commission and Board of Dock Commissioners. Walter H. Taylor, Jr. served as the first director of the department.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of files of working drawings from the Norfolk Department of Public Works, presumably for demolished or otherwise obsolete structures. It documents a number of municipal projects from the early 1900s, such as armories, cemeteries, fire stations, hospitals, jails, markets, parks, police facilities, schools, and sewerage / drainage facilities. In many cases additional notations are made to the original plans to record modifications to structures.
Among the best documented project types are those for fire stations. Included are drawings of wharf facilities for the fire boat "Vulcan."
Arrangement
Alphabetically according to project type (Armories, Cemeteries, Fire Department, Hospitals, Jails, Markets, Miscellanious Drawings, Parks, Police Facilities, Schools, and Sewerage / Drainage Facilities) and chronologically there under.
Contents List
- Armory - Armory Building for City of Norfolk on Princess Anne Avenue near Monticello Ave., Norfolk, Virginia, 1923, Dimensions: 60 x 76 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: K. L. Hulsick Comopany / Architects & Engineers / 400 Flat Iron Bldg., Norfolk, Va.
- Armory - [Structural steel details], 1923, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: Liberty Iron & Wire Co., Inc. / Office: McKevitt Bldg. / Plant: Olney Road & Matoka St., Norfolk, Va.
- Armory - Additions to Present Gun Shed Princess Anne Road for City of Norfolk, Va., 1930, Dimensions: 27 x 46 cm.; Scale: 3/8" = 1'; Media: 1 Pencil on tracing paper, 4 blueprints; Sheets: 5 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: Unsigned
- Armory - Doors & Windows for Add to Present Gun Shed Norfolk, Va., 1930, Dimensions: 46 x 62 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: Truscon Steel Company / Norfolk, Va.
- Armory - [Structural steel plans], n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints with colored pencil notations; Sheets: 2 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: Miller Engineering Corp.
- Armory - [Structural steel plans, detail, and specifications for Norfolk armory], n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 15 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: Milliken Brothers Mfg. Co. Inc. / Woolworth Bldg., New York
- Armory - [Calculations and profiles for excavations], n.d., Dimensions: 33 x 48 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and red pencil on printed forms; Sheets: 2 (Folder N33)
  Drawn By: J. T. Neely
- Cemetery - Alterations to Sup'ts House Elmwood Cemetery Norfolk, 1917, Dimensions: 73 x 66 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N31)
  Drawn By: Rossel Edward Mitchell Arch't
- Cemetery - New Entrance Gates Cedar Grove & Elmwood Cemeteries Princess Anne Road, Norfolk, Va., 1927, Dimensions: 39 x 78 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N31)
  Drawn By: Drawn by: J. T. Neely
- Cemetery - New Gates, Piers and Paving at Entrances to Cedar Grove & Elmwood Cemeteries, City of Norfolk, Va., 1929, Dimensions: 38 x 68 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N31)
  Drawn By: [Approval signature of W. H. Taylor, Director of Public Works and J. T. Neely]
- Cemetery - [Utility building (?)] Verso: Cedar Grove Cemetery & Elmwood Cemetery, n.d., Dimensions: 30 x 37 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N31)
- Cemetery - [Study sketch for entrance gates], n.d., Dimensions: 36 x 52 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil on back of City of Norfolk forms: "Building Operations"; Sheets: 2 (Folder N31)
- Cemetery - Office Building / Elmwood Cemetery for the City of Norfolk / Virginia, n.d., Dimensions: 61 x 87 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N31)
  Drawn By: Wickham C. Taylor / Architect / Norfolk, Virginia
- City Hall - Addition to Lamberts Point School, Norfolk, Virginia, 1920, Dimensions: 64 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 6 (Folder N15)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson - Architects / & Engineers / Norkfolk, Virginia
- Fire Department - Brambleton Fire Engine House, Norfolk City, 1903, Dimensions: 44 x 47 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 18 (Folder N21)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson - Architects / Norfolk, Virginia
- Fire Department - Alterations at Fire Department Headquarters for the City of Norfolk Virginia, 1905, Dimensions: 70 x 76 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: 6 Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen, 6 blueprints; Sheets: 12 (Folder N18)
  Drawn By: F. F. Ferguson & Chas. J. Calrow / Architects - Norfolk
- Fire Department - Fire Station for the Sixth Ward of the City of Norfolk Virginia, 1905, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: 5 Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen, 5 blueprints; Sheets: 10 (Folder N24)
  Drawn By: F. F. Ferguson & Chas. J. Calrow - Architiects
- Fire Department - 1-1/2 Inch Scale Elevation of Switch Board Fire Dep't Headquarters Norfolk, Va., 1906, Dimensions: 37 x 30 cm.; Scale: 1-1/2" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and blue ink on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N19)
  Drawn By: Ferguson & Calrow - Arch't / Norfolk Va.
- Fire Department - 3/4 in. Scale Detail of Cabinet Around Sliding Pole Opening in Chief's Room Fire Dept. Headquarters - Norfolk, Va., 1906, Dimensions: 47 x 37 cm.; Scale: 3/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil and yellow pencil on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N19)
  Drawn By: [F. F. Ferguson & Chas. J. Calrow]
- Fire Department - Bearing Plates - Belly Rod Truss Alterations at Fire Department Headquarters, 1906, Dimensions: 64 x 84 cm.; Scale: Full scale; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N19)
- Fire Department - 3/4 scale of doors (except front doors) 6th Ward Fire Station Norfolk City, 1906, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 3/4 in. = 1 ft.; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N24)
  Drawn By: Ferguson & Calrow - Archts
- Fire Department - [Plaque for Fire Station No. 6 - two versions], 1906, Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and India ink on tracing paper; Sheets: 2 (Folder N24)
  Drawn By: [Ferguson and Calrow]
- Fire Department - Fire Department Headquarters Erected AD 1871 Remodeled AD 1906...[plaque], 1906, Dimensions: 38 x 26 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder N18)
  Drawn By: [F. F. Ferguson & C. J. Calrow]
- Fire Department - Fire Station - Cor. 12th. St. & Monticello Ave. for The City of Norfolk, Virginia, 1911, Dimensions: 43 x 58 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints with pencil notations; Sheets: 9 (Folder N23)
  Drawn By: B. F. Mitchell - Architect
- Fire Department - Fire Alarm Telegraph Station for the City of Norfolk, Va., 1912, Dimensions: 48 x 88 c.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 3 (Folder N22)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson Architects
- Fire Department - Steel & Miscellanious Iron Ocean View Fire House, 1922, Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N23)
  Drawn By: P. B. Moser Arch't - S. Tars Contractor / Standard Iron Works Inc.
- Fire Department - Addition to Fire Alarm Station, 1922, Dimensions: 39 x 102 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N22)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson Architects & Engineers
- Fire Department - Cast Iron Columns Ocean View Fire Station, 1922, Dimensions: 47 x 41 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N23)
- Fire Department - Steel & Miscellaneous Iron for Fire Station, Haynes Ave. & Broad Creek Rd., 1923, Dimensions: 61 x 92 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N13)
  Drawn By: Standard Iron Works...
- Fire Department - Fire Station for the Department of Public Safety Norfolk Virginia Located on the South East Cor. Of Haynes Ave. & Broad Creek Road, 1923, Dimensions: 64 x 39 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 9 (Folder N13)
  Drawn By: Philip B. Moser & / Erwin C. Gutzwiller / Architects & Engineers / Law B'ld'g - Norfolk, Va.
- Fire Department - Quarters for Firemen Fireboat 'Vulcan' City of Norfolk, Va., 1923, Dimensions: 58 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N32)
- Fire Department - Alterations to Timber Wharf to Accommodate Fire Boat 'Vulcan', 1923, Dimensions: 40 x 48 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper and blueprint; Sheets: 3 (Folder N32)
- Fire Department - Remodeling of Building for Fire Station for the Department of Public Safety Norfolk Virginia Located on A Avenue, Ocean View, Norfolk, Virginia, 1923, Dimensions: 68 39 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8 (Folder N23)
- Fire Department - Details of stalls in toilet for the Fire Station in the Sixth Ward of the City of Norfolk Virginia, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N24)
- Fire Department - [Details of doors on Fire Department Headquarters], n.d., Dimensions: 156 x 87 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N19)
  Drawn By: Ferguson & Calrow - Arch't
- Fire Department - Crew's Quarters Fire Boat 'Vulcan', n.d., Dimensions: 46 x 67 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6 (Folder N32)
- Fire Department - Automobile Repair & Machine Shop for the Department of Public Safety - Norfolk, Virginia Located on the S. E. Cor. Of Montecello Ave. & Twelfth Street, n.d., Dimensions: 51 x 77 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 5 (Folder N34)
- Fire Department - Verso: Chief Petey's Original Layout of Crew's Quarters" [of fire boat "Vulcan"], n.d., Dimensions: 58 x 28 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil on heavy paper. Two sheets are on reverse of City of Norfolk Fire Department payroll form dated "190_"; Sheets: 5 (Folder N32)
- Hospital - Tuberculosis Building for the City of Norfolk, Va., 1929, Dimensions: 57 x 109 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 4 (Folder N30)
  Drawn By: Calrow, Browne, & Fitz-Gibbon, Architects
- Hospital - Chas. R. Grandy Sanatorium for the City of Norfolk, Virginia, 1931, Dimensions: 67 x 120 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N30)
  Drawn By: Calrow, Browne, & Fitz-Gibbon, Architects - Norfolk, Virginia
- Hospital - City Contagious Hospital Norfolk, Va., n.d., Dimensions: 45 x 81 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7 (Folder N36)
  Drawn By: Wickham C. Taylor - Architect / Norfolk, Va.
- Hospital - Isolation Hospital Unit for the City of Norfolk, Virginia, n.d., Dimensions: 57 x 118 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 5 (Folder N30)
- Jail - Plan of Prison Farm, 1929, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 8 (Folder N01)
  Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Norfolk, Va.
- Jail - Dormitory Municipal Prison Farm, 1930, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints with pencil notations; Sheets: 4 (Folder N03)
  Drawn By: City of Norfolk, Virginia, / Dept. of Public Works / Div. Of Building Inspection
- Jail - Convict Camp [plans for barracks, mess hall, and guard's quarters], n.d., Dimensions: 47 x 32 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints with pencil notations; Sheets: 3 (Folder N01)
  Drawn By: Department of Public Welfare / State of Virginia
- Jail - Convct Camp Mess Table, n.d., Dimensions: 27 x 31 cm.; Scale: 1-1/2" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N01)
- Library - Branch Public Library - Norfolk Va., 1913, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: 18 India ink and yellow ink on linen, 9 blueprints; Sheets: 26 (Folder N28)
  Drawn By: Ferguson, Calrow & Taylor - Architects
- Library - Roof and Suspended Ceilings Branch Public Library Norfolk, Va., 1915, Dimensions: 59 x 87 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N28)
  Drawn By: Trussed Concrete Steel Co. / Washington Office
- Library - Leaded Glass Work for Ceiling Light / Branch Library Norfolk, Va., n.d., Dimensions: 32 x 37 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N28)
  Drawn By: Ferguson, Calron, & Wrenn Arch'ts
- Library - Skylight Branch Library Norfolk, Va., n.d., Dimensions: 39 x 64 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N28)
- Library - Detail of Brick Arches East and West Elevations Branch Public Library - Norfolk Va., n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: 18 India ink and yellow ink on linen, 9 blueprints; Sheets: 26 (Folder N28)
- Library - Unidentified, n.d., Dimensions: 31 x 27 cm.; Scale: None; Media: None; Sheets: (Folder N28)
- Market - Shelters for City of Norfolk Va., 1923, Dimensions: 32 x 77 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 2 India ink and red ink on linen, 5 blueprints; Sheets: 5 (Folder N05)
  Drawn By: W. H. Taylor / Director of Public Works
- Market - Flower Market Tazwell St. - South End of City Market / City of Norfolk, Va., 1924, Dimensions: 44 x 71 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N05)
  Drawn By: Approved / W. H. Taylor / Director of Public Works
- Market - Shelter Shed for City of Norfolk, Va., 1926, Dimensions: 33 x 66 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 1 pencil on tracing paper, 4 blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N05)
- Market - Flower Booths for Market" [verso: Original Design of Flower Market], n.d., Dimensions: 56 x 79 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 1 India ink and red ink on linen with pencil notations, 1 blueprint with pencil notations; Sheets: 2 (Folder N05)
- Other - Dog Pound to be Erected on Princess Anne Road, 1929, Dimensions: 61 x 86 cm; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: 5 Blueprints, 4 pencil on tracing paper, 1 pencil on graph paper; Sheets: 10 (Folder N02)
- Other - [Miscellaneous specifications and documents], n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: None; Sheets: (Folder N38)
- Other - Additions & Alterations to Detention Home for the City of Norfolk, Virginia, Welfare Center, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7 (Folder N30)
- Other - Hospital Ward for the Almshouse, n.d., Dimensions: 41 x 64 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N30)
  Drawn By: John Kevan Peebles - Architect - Norfolk, Va.
- Park - City Park Green House, 1899, Dimensions: 58 x 92 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprints with colored pencil notations; Sheets: 2 (Folder N26)
  Drawn By: Arnold Eberhard Architect / Norfolk, Va.
- Park - Proposed Building at the Zoological Gardens Lafayette Park - Norfolk, Va., 1906, Dimensions: 58 x 83 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N26)
  Drawn By: Arnold Eberhard / Architect / Norfolk, Va.
- Park - Animal Houses / City Park, 1923, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 5 (Folder N37)
  Drawn By: Walker-Smith Co. Inc. / Norfolk, Va. and Archt: J. T. Neely
- Park - Animal Cages & Runways Lafayette Park City of Norfolk, Va., 1923, Dimensions: 53 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: 1 Pencil on paper, 2 blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N37)
  Drawn By: J. T. Neely, City Structural Engineer
- Park - Public Comfort Station / Lafayette Park, 1930, Dimensions: 60 x 86 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N26)
  Drawn By: City of Norfolk, Virginia / Dept. Public Works, / Div. Buildig IUnsignedpection
- Park - [Plan, sections, and details of public swimming pool], 1934, Dimensions: 65 x 98 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N26)
  Drawn By: [Various approval signatures]
- Park - Verso: Stable Laf[ayette] Park, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil on heavy paper; Sheets: 4 (Folder N26)
- Park - City Park Waiting Room, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder N34)
  Drawn By: J. E. R. Carpenter / Architect / 51 Granby St. Norfolk, Va.
- Park - Pavillion for City Park [perspective drawing], n.d., Dimensions: 39 x 56 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and India ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N25)
  Drawn By: H. I. Dwyer. Arc'ht. / Norfolk, Va.
- Park - Entrance to City Park, n.d., Dimensions: 47 x 91 cm.; Scale: 3/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N26)
  Drawn By: Mac
- Park - [City Park Summer House], n.d., Dimensions: 44 x 62 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Diazo print with subsequent inked lines and notations; Sheets: 5 (Folder N27)
  Drawn By: Arnold Eberhard Arch't
- Park - [Elevation and plans for Pavillion for City Park], n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N25)
  Drawn By: A. I. Dwyer Architect / West Building / Norfolk, Va.
- Police - City of Norfolk Police Headquarters Norfolk Va. First Precinct Station & Police Court, 1910, Dimensions: 72 x 100 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints with pencil notations; Sheets: 12 (Folder N04)
  Drawn By: John Keynan Peebles, Norfolk, Va. / Architect
- Police - Police Station Building for City of Norfolk, Virginia on Avenue B, Ocean View, Norfolk, Va., 1923, Dimensions: 46 x 94 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder N22)
- Police - Proposed Alterations of Police Headquarters in the City of Norfolk, Virginia, 1925, Dimensions: 73 x 86 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: 3 Pencil, India ink, and yellow ink on linen, 2 pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 5 (Folder N39)
  Drawn By: Drawn by R. L. Holland -- Traced by C. P. Machen
- Police - [Fifth Precinct Police Station at Titustown], n.d., Dimensions: 21 x 27 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder N04)
- School - Addition to Cumberland Street School Norfolk, Va., 1905, Dimensions: 28 x 62 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 7 (Folder N29)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson Archs.
- School - Addition to Cumberland Street School Norfolk, Va., 1906, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 7 (Folder N29)
- School - Brambleton Public School Number 1, Norfolk, Va., 1910, Dimensions: 54 x 92 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (faded); Sheets: 2 (Folder N35)
  Drawn By: Ferguson, Calrow and Taylor - Architects
- School - Building for the Colored Grammer School Berkley Ward - Norfolk Virginia, 1911, Dimensions: 71 x 117 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint with pencil notations; Sheets: 6 (Folder N09)
  Drawn By: Lee & Diehl / Architects / Norfolk, Virginia
- School - New Grammer School / for Norfolk, Virginia, 1913, Dimensions: 59 x 69 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 8 (Folder N14)
  Drawn By: Neff & Thompson - Architects
- School - Walter Herron Taylor School for the City of Norfolk, Virginia, 1916, Dimensions: 57 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Blueprints (2 sets of 13 drawings); Sheets: 26 (Folder N17)
  Drawn By: John Kevan Peebles - Architect - Norfolk, Virginia
- School - J. J. Smallwood School for the City of Norfolk Virginia, 1919, Dimensions: 45 x 63 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 12 Pencil, India ink, brown ink, and red ink on linen, 10 blueprints; Sheets: 22 (Folder N06)
  Drawn By: John Kevan Peebles / Findlay F. Ferguson / Architects / Norfolk, Va.
- School - Detail of Accordian Doors J. J. Smallwood School for the City of Norfolk, Va., 1919, Dimensions: 53 x 74 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N06)
  Drawn By: Peebles & Ferguson - Architects / Norfolk, Va.
- School - F. S. Detail of Cornice Lott Carey School Princess Anne Ave. - Norfolk Va., 1919, Dimensions: 64 x 50 cm.; Scale: Full scale; Media: Pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N08)
  Drawn By: Peebles and Ferguson - Architects / Norfolk - Va.
- School - Lott Carey School for the City of Norfolk Virginia, 1919, Dimensions: 45 x 75 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 9 (Folder N08)
  Drawn By: John Kevan Peebles and Findlay F. Ferguson - Architects / Norfolk Va.
- School - [Chart detailing temperature information for Lee and Madison schools in winter 1919 - 1920], 1919, Dimensions: 26 x 52 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N35)
- School - [Charts detailing heating and ventilation conditions and their effects in 11 city schools], 1919 (?), Dimensions: 36 x 98 cm.; Scale: None; Media: pencil on paper; Sheets: 2 (Folder N35)
- School - New Passage Connecting Old and New Buildings Lott Carey School for the City of Norfolk, Virginia, 1920, Dimensions: 53 x 47 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil and India ink on tracing paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder N08)
  Drawn By: Peebles and Ferguson - Arch'ts
- School - Air Supply for Heating System Stonewall Jackson School Norfolk, Virginia, 1920, Dimensions: 32 x 80 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 1 Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder N20)
  Drawn By: Peebles and Ferguson Architects / Norfolk, Va.
- School - Fresh Air Grille Robert E. Lee School Norfolk, Virginia, 1920, Dimensions: 2 x 28 cm.; Scale: None; Media: 1 Pencil on tracing paper, 1 blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder N35)
  Drawn By: Pebles & Ferguson Architects / Norfolk, Virginia
- School - Addition to James Madison School for the City of Norfolk, Va., 1921, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder N15)
- School - Fire Escapes of Rear of Larchmont School & Ballentine Place School for School Board - City of Norfolk, Va., 1923, Dimensions: 57 x 92 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 6 (Folder N12)
  Drawn By: Atlantic Iron Works / Norfolk, Virginia
- School - Annex to School at Compostella Heights Norfolk, Va., 1924, Dimensions: 67 x 91 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder N12)
  Drawn By: Norfolk Iron & Wire Works, Inc. / Norfolk, Va.
- School - Annex to School at Compostella Heights Norfolk, Va., 1924, Dimensions: 68 x 74 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints with red pencil notations; Sheets: 9 (Folder N12)
  Drawn By: W. Newton Diehl / Certified / Architect / New Monroe Building / Norfolk, Virginia
- School - [Structural steel plans for Lafayette School], 1928, Dimensions: 60 x 90 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 4 (Folder N11)
  Drawn By: Architect: Peebles & Ferguson / Contractor: R. R. Richardson
- School - Lafayette School for the City of Norfolk Virgina, 1928, Dimensions: 21 x 76 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 16 (Folder N11)
  Drawn By: Peebles and Ferguson Architects